FiberPatrol, from Senstar, is a high-performance
fiber optic perimeter intrusion detection
system.
With its extended coverage distance and precision
ranging, FiberPatrol is ideal for protecting
critical sites and infrastructure.
Software-defined zones with independent detection
settings enable a single sensor cable to detect
activity across a mix of applications, including
chainlink, welded mesh and pallisade fences,
wall tops, buried perimeter, buried pipeline
interference, and data conduits.
FiberPatrol locates intrusions to within a
few meters.
Adaptive signal processing combined with experiential
intelligence immediately detects and locates
intrusions, providing security staff with
enhanced situational awareness and precise
camera pointing capabilities.
The fiber optic sensor is lightning and EMI
immune, intrinsically safe in explosive environments,
and contains no in-infield electrical components.
FiberPatrol technology works by measuring
the Rayleigh backscattering of highly coherent
laser light along the fiber, enabling the
precise detection and locating of any disturbance.
In addition, the system offers cut-immunity,
in which the full perimeter remains protected
in the event of a cable cut.
Multi-layered signal processing, including
environmental disaggregation alongside environmentally
derived adaptive processing technology (EDAPT),
enables FiberPatrol to detect intrusion attempts
while filtering out noise from environmental
conditions like wind or rain, virtually eliminating
nuisance alarms that may overload the ability
of the security staff to respond.
The FiberPatrol sensor unit includes all necessary
detection and gateway software, and supports
certified integrations with industry ~~leading~~-leading
security software.
An open, freely available SDK ensures FiberPatrol
can be easily added to any security system.
Part of a comprehensive portfolio of security
products, FiberPatrol is backed by worldwide
technical support from a security company
trusted for over 40 years.