we are proud to present our newest state
of the art fiber sensor for long
perimeters with accurate intrusion
location a single processor with a
standard fiber cable can protect long
perimeters these could be different
types of physical barriers such as
welded mesh
Jean link fence
top walls
and buried pipelines the technology
leverages the phenomena that when light
travels in a fiber a fraction of the
photons scatter back to the source this
return carries valuable information
regarding intrusions the processor acts
like radar pulses of light are
transmitted and in between back
scattered energy is measured and
displayed correlated to the time of
travel when the fiber is static the
display shows no spikes an intrusion
would shake a section of the fiber and a
spike would show due to the change in
the nature of the back scattered energy
a redundant configuration with
Streamlight clockwise and
counterclockwise simultaneously enabling
full functionality even if the cable is
cut the extended range system for
pipelines
minimizes the number of infrastructure
locations where equipment needs to be
installed fiber Patrol delivers accurate
location of intruders detects multiple
simultaneous intrusions no need for
outdoor power or electronics EMI and
lightning immunity superb ease of
installation and self-healing in case of
a fiber cut fiber Patrol an innovative
security solution for airports borders
energy and utility and any other long
perimeter or pipeline application