A fence around the perimeter of a secured site is only a minor deterrent for determined intruders.
The FlexZone fence sensor brings intrusion detection out to the perimeter,
protecting against trespassing vandalism and theft while helping to meet security requirements.
FlexZone is a fence-mounted perimeter intrusion detection system
that detects and locates attempts to cut climb or otherwise break through a perimeter fence.
FlexZone combines many of the most advanced security features into a single cost-effective solution.
Unlike less advanced solutions on the market, FlexZone uses software-defined zones.
Each processor supports up to 60 zones,
all independently adjustable and readily integrated with cameras for complete coverage.
FlexZone covers 2,000 feet or 600 meters per processor and locates intrusions within 10 feet or 3 meters,
industry-leading performance at a fraction of the cost. The system provides security staff with enhanced
situational awareness and precise camera pointing capabilities.
FlexZone uses adaptive algorithms to detect
simultaneous intrusion attempts while filtering out noise from environmental conditions like wind or rain,
virtually eliminating nuisance alarms that may overload the ability of the security staff to respond.
FlexZone can be installed on almost any fence type including chain-link welded mesh and palisade.
Installation is simple: with FlexZone a single cable carry sensor data,
networking and power and can be quickly installed on the fence by non specialized personnel.
Ruggedized for the outdoors, FlexZone works even in the most extreme weather conditions.
FlexZone is compatible with more than 20 third-party solutions and is easily added to any existing security system.
Part of a comprehensive portfolio of security products, FlexZone is backed by worldwide technical support
from a security company trusted for over 35 years.
Senstar --
Safeguarding people places and property