OmniTrax is a leading buried
cable intrusion detection sensor.
The best coverage is achieved when the
transmitting and receiving cables
are buried one to two meters apart,
creating an invisible radar-like detection
field of about three meters wide.
If an intruder disrupts the electromagnetic field
it will cause an alarm with accurate
location to the nearest one meter.
A single OmniTrax processor covers two
segments, each of these up to 400 meters.
For longer perimeters processors can be networked.
The sensor cables can also provide power and data.
OmniTrax is completely covert and
therefore extremely difficult to defeat.
The detection accuracy enables precise
pointing of a camera to the suspected location.
OmniTrax is a terrain-following covert
sensor and extremely difficult to defeat.
With accurate locating, it is a high
security sensor, ideal for maintaining
site aesthetics or as part of an integrated
perimeter intrusion detection system.