The Senstar LM100 is the world's first
intelligent perimeter lighting and
sensing solution. The luminaire combines
high-performance LED lighting with
intrusion detection sensors. A powerful
deterrent the LM100 detects and
illuminates intruders at the fence line
simple to install the Senstar LM100
enhances your perimeter security, while
saving you money by reducing operational
costs and protecting against break-ins.
The LM100 is designed to protect any
property or site with perimeter security
requirements. It can be used as a
standalone system or in conjunction with
CCTV cameras and other security products
uniform illumination of the fence line
helps CCTV cameras to avoid bright spots,
while high color rendering index LEDs
ensure colors are not washed out.
Built-in sensors notify your security
system of any attempt to cut, climb, lift
or break the fence fabric. The lights can
follow a pre-programmed schedule as well
as turn on or strobe whenever intrusion
attempts are detected.
Wireless networking eliminates the need to install communication cabling along the
fence. It forms a self-healing mesh
ensuring that the system remains
operational if some of the luminaires
are damaged. A low-voltage device, the LM100
is easy and safe to install, and the
downward directed coverage pattern
minimizes light pollution. Using only 2.5
watts per luminaire the ultra
energy-efficient LM100 reduces
electricity costs by as much as 95% when
compared to other security lighting
products.
Built by Senstar, the world leader in
perimeter intrusion detection systems
the Senstar LM100 combines two
security technologies into a single
system. It is an affordable effective way
to protect any property.