The Senstar FiberPatrol FP400 is a fence-mounted
fiber optic sensor
that detects perimeter intrusions.
With 4 separate detection zones, the FP400
is an affordable solution for smaller sites
where EMI, lightning or in-field electrical
components are a concern.
The lightweight fiber optic sensor cable is
attached directly to the fence fabric.
Any attempt to cut, climb, or otherwise break
through the fence disturbs the transmitted
signal and an alarm is generated.
The FP400 works on most fence types, including
chainlink, welded mesh, and palisade.
The processor is outdoor-rated and can be
installed in a variety of locations to meet
deployment requirements.
For example, it can be installed outside along
the perimeter itself, or placed in a central
secure location and connect to the perimeter
via non-sensing lead-in cable.
As part of Senstar’s family of perimeter
protection solutions, the FP400 is easy to
set up and works with Senstar’s entire suite
of software for configuration, integration,
and alarm display.
Field-proven integrations for industry-standard
security and video management systems are
available, minimizing training requirements.
Designed by the world leader in perimeter
intrusion detection systems, the FiberPatrol
FP400 is an affordable, effective way to protect
smaller sites.