Ultra wave is an intelligent by static
microwave intrusion detection sensor
it's an ideal solution for protecting
gates open areas rooftops and walls an
invisible electromagnetic field of
energy is created between the
transmitter and receiver digital signal
processing algorithms analyze changes in
the field and distinguish intruders
running walking or crawling from
background noise and environmental
effects ultra-wave provides a low
nuisance alarm rate while maintaining a
high probability of detection to protect
against deliberate spoofing or
accidental misalignment the ultra wave
receiver unit only recognizes its paired
transmitter unit through a unique
microwave communication channel between
the devices this communications channel
reduces infrastructure costs by
eliminating the need to run networking
cable to the transmitter unit with 10
options for frequency channels
ultra-wave pairs can be deployed
individually or stacked together to
increase the height of the detection
zone like all send star products
the ultra wave has been designed for and
tested in harsh outdoor environments and
works with sin stars entire product
suite for networking configuration
integration and alarm display field
proven integrations for industry
standards security and video management
systems are available minimizing
training requirements designed by the
world leader in perimeter intrusion
detection systems ultra-wave provides a
high level of security performance for
critical infrastructure oil and gas
logistics and correctional facilities
[Music]